[
    {
        "answer": "a fictional sword and sorcery hero",
        "question": "What is Conan the Barbarian?",
        "sentence": "\nConan the Barbarian ( also known as Conan the Cimmerian ) is a fictional sword and sorcery hero who originated in pulp magazines and has since been adapted to books , comics , films ( including Conan the Barbarian and Conan the Destroyer ) , television programs ( animated and live - action ) , video games , and role - playing games ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1932",
        "question": "When was the character created?",
        "sentence": "Robert E. Howard created the character in 1932 for a series of fantasy stories published in Weird Tales magazine ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Weird Tales",
        "question": "What magazine did Robert E. Howard create the character for?",
        "sentence": "Robert E. Howard created the character in 1932 for a series of fantasy stories published in Weird Tales magazine ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1932",
        "question": "When was Conan the Barbarian published?",
        "sentence": "Robert E. Howard created Conan the Barbarian in a series of fantasy stories published in Weird Tales from 1932 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Robert E. Howard",
        "question": "Who created Conan the Barbarian?",
        "sentence": "Robert E. Howard created Conan the Barbarian in a series of fantasy stories published in Weird Tales from 1932 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Crom",
        "question": "What deity does Conan swear by?",
        "sentence": "People of the Dark \" is a story about the remembrance of \" past lives \" , and in its first - person narrative , the protagonist describes one of his previous incarnations ; Conan is a black - haired barbarian hero who swears by a deity called Crom ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Howard",
        "question": "Who believed Conan was a forerunner of the more famous character?",
        "sentence": "Some Howard scholars believe this Conan to be a forerunner of the more famous character ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Thomas Bulfinch",
        "question": "Who wrote The Outline of Mythology?",
        "sentence": "According to some scholars , Howard 's conception of Conan and the Hyborian Age may have originated in Thomas Bulfinch 's The Outline of Mythology ( 1913 ) which inspired Howard to \" coalesce into a coherent whole his literary aspirations and the strong physical , autobiographical elements underlying the creation of Conan\" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Thomas Bulfinch",
        "question": "Who wrote The Outline of Mythology?",
        "sentence": "According to some scholars , Howard 's conception of Conan and the Hyborian Age may have originated in Thomas Bulfinch 's The Outline of Mythology ( 1913 ) which inspired Howard to \" coalesce into a coherent whole his literary aspirations and the strong physical , autobiographical elements underlying the creation of Conan\" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Outline of Mythology",
        "question": "What book may have inspired Howard to coalesce into a coherent whole?",
        "sentence": "According to some scholars , Howard 's conception of Conan and the Hyborian Age may have originated in Thomas Bulfinch 's The Outline of Mythology ( 1913 ) which inspired Howard to \" coalesce into a coherent whole his literary aspirations and the strong physical , autobiographical elements underlying the creation of Conan\" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Phoenix on the Sword",
        "question": "What was the name of the new character he replaced Kull of Atlantis with?",
        "sentence": "( May 1929 ) , replacing his existing character Kull of Atlantis with his new hero and retitling it \" The Phoenix on the Sword \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "May 1929",
        "question": "When was 'The Phoenix on the Sword' released?",
        "sentence": "( May 1929 ) , replacing his existing character Kull of Atlantis with his new hero and retitling it \" The Phoenix on the Sword \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Hyborian Age",
        "question": "What was the fictional setting for Conan?",
        "sentence": "Editor Farnsworth Wright subsequently prompted Howard to write an 8,000-word essay for personal use detailing \" the Hyborian Age \" , the fictional setting for Conan ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Conan",
        "question": "Who was the fictional setting for the Hyborian Age?",
        "sentence": "Editor Farnsworth Wright subsequently prompted Howard to write an 8,000-word essay for personal use detailing \" the Hyborian Age \" , the fictional setting for Conan ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Tower of the Elephant",
        "question": "What was the first Conan story to integrate his new conception of the Hyborian world?",
        "sentence": "Using this essay as his guideline , Howard began plotting \" The Tower of the Elephant \" , a new Conan story that was the first to integrate his new conception of the Hyborian world ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Tower of the Elephant",
        "question": "What book inspired Howard to write more Conan stories for Weird Tales?",
        "sentence": "The publication and success of \" The Tower of the Elephant \" spurred Howard to write more Conan stories for Weird Tales ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Howard",
        "question": "Who wrote more Conan stories for Weird Tales?",
        "sentence": "The publication and success of \" The Tower of the Elephant \" spurred Howard to write more Conan stories for Weird Tales ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "40 years",
        "question": "How long did Howard's Conan stories remain out of print?",
        "sentence": "For roughly 40 years , the original versions of Howard 's Conan stories remained out of print ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "the 1980s and 1990s",
        "question": "When did the copyright holders allow Howard's stories to go out of print?",
        "sentence": "In the 1980s and 1990s , the copyright holders permitted Howard 's stories to go out of print entirely , while continuing to sell Conan works by other authors ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Gollancz Science Fiction",
        "question": "What publisher published Howard's Conan stories in 2000?",
        "sentence": "In 2000 , the British publisher Gollancz Science Fiction issued a two - volume , complete edition of Howard 's Conan stories as part of its Fantasy Masterworks imprint , which included several stories that had never seen print in their original form ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "2000",
        "question": "In what year did Gollancz Science Fiction release a two volume, complete edition of Howard's Conan stories?",
        "sentence": "In 2000 , the British publisher Gollancz Science Fiction issued a two - volume , complete edition of Howard 's Conan stories as part of its Fantasy Masterworks imprint , which included several stories that had never seen print in their original form ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Complete Chronicles of Conan : Centenary Edition",
        "question": "What were the stories restored to chronological order as?",
        "sentence": "The two volumes were combined and the stories restored to chronological order as The Complete Chronicles of Conan : Centenary Edition ( Gollancz Science Fiction , 2006 ; edited and with an Afterword by Steve Jones ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Steve Jones",
        "question": "Who wrote the Afterword for The Complete Chronicles of Conan?",
        "sentence": "The two volumes were combined and the stories restored to chronological order as The Complete Chronicles of Conan : Centenary Edition ( Gollancz Science Fiction , 2006 ; edited and with an Afterword by Steve Jones ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Wandering Star Books",
        "question": "What publisher made an effort to restore Howard's original manuscripts?",
        "sentence": "In 2003 , another British publisher , Wandering Star Books , made an effort both to restore Howard 's original manuscripts and to provide a more scholarly and historical view of the Conan stories ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Coming of Conan the Cimmerian",
        "question": "What was the name of the first volume of Conan of Cimmeria published in the US?",
        "sentence": "The first book , Conan of Cimmeria : Volume One ( 1932\u20131933 ) ( 2003 ; published in the US as The Coming of Conan the Cimmerian ) includes Howard 's notes on his fictional setting as well as letters and poems concerning the genesis of his ideas ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Bloody Crown of Conan",
        "question": "What was the title of Conan of Cimmeria : Volume Two?",
        "sentence": "This was followed by Conan of Cimmeria : Volume Two ( 1934 ) ( 2004 ; published in the US as The Bloody Crown of Conan ) and Conan of Cimmeria : Volume Three ( 1935\u20131936 ) ( 2005 ; published in the US as The Conquering Sword of Conan ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Conan of Cimmeria : Volume Two",
        "question": "What was the name of the book that followed The Bloody Crown of Conan?",
        "sentence": "This was followed by Conan of Cimmeria : Volume Two ( 1934 ) ( 2004 ; published in the US as The Bloody Crown of Conan ) and Conan of Cimmeria : Volume Three ( 1935\u20131936 ) ( 2005 ; published in the US as The Conquering Sword of Conan ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "all the original Conan stories",
        "question": "What is included in these three volumes?",
        "sentence": "These three volumes include all the original Conan stories ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Phoenix on the Sword",
        "question": "What is the name of the book where Conan's adventures take place?",
        "sentence": "According to \" The Phoenix on the Sword \" , the adventures of Conan take place \" Between the years when the oceans drank Atlantis and the gleaming cities , and the years of the rise of the Sons of Aryas . \""
    },
    {
        "answer": "Cimmerian",
        "question": "What type of person is Conan?",
        "sentence": "Conan is a Cimmerian ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "village blacksmith",
        "question": "What was Conan's father's occupation?",
        "sentence": "Conan was born on a battlefield and is the son of a village blacksmith ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "fifteen",
        "question": "At what age was Conan a respected warrior?",
        "sentence": "Conan matured quickly as a youth and , by age fifteen , he was already a respected warrior who had participated in the destruction of the Aquilonian fortress of Venarium ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "warrior",
        "question": "What was Conan's profession?",
        "sentence": "Conan matured quickly as a youth and , by age fifteen , he was already a respected warrior who had participated in the destruction of the Aquilonian fortress of Venarium ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "wanderlust",
        "question": "What was Howard struck by after the film's death?",
        "sentence": "After its demise , he was struck by wanderlust and began the adventures chronicled by Howard , encountering skulking monsters , evil wizards , tavern wenches , and beautiful princesses ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "skulking monsters",
        "question": "What kind of monsters did Howard encounter?",
        "sentence": "After its demise , he was struck by wanderlust and began the adventures chronicled by Howard , encountering skulking monsters , evil wizards , tavern wenches , and beautiful princesses ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Hyborian Age",
        "question": "During what era did he roam as a thief, outlaw, mercenary, and pirate?",
        "sentence": "He roamed throughout the Hyborian Age nations as a thief , outlaw , mercenary , and pirate ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "pirate",
        "question": "Along with thief, outlaw, mercenary, and mercenary, what was he also known as?",
        "sentence": "He roamed throughout the Hyborian Age nations as a thief , outlaw , mercenary , and pirate ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "warriors",
        "question": "As he grew older, he began commanding vast units of what kind of troops?",
        "sentence": "As he grew older , he began commanding vast units of warriors and escalating his ambitions ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "tyrannical king of Aquilonia",
        "question": "Who was the most powerful kingdom of the Hyborian Age?",
        "sentence": "In his forties , he seized the crown from the tyrannical king of Aquilonia , the most powerful kingdom of the Hyborian Age , having strangled the previous ruler on the steps of his own throne ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "to protect his own survival or for personal gain",
        "question": "What is Conan's motivation for performing heroic feats?",
        "sentence": "Conan 's adventures often result in him performing heroic feats , though his motivation for doing so is largely to protect his own survival or for personal gain ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "heroic feats",
        "question": "What does Conan perform in his adventures?",
        "sentence": "Conan 's adventures often result in him performing heroic feats , though his motivation for doing so is largely to protect his own survival or for personal gain ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "his chivalry",
        "question": "What is a conspicuous element of Conan's character?",
        "sentence": "A conspicuous element of Conan 's character is his chivalry ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "damsel",
        "question": "Who does he have a strong tendency to save in distress?",
        "sentence": "He is extremely reluctant to fight women ( even when they fight him ) and has a strong tendency to save a damsel in distress ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jewels of Gwahlur",
        "question": "What is the name of the movie in which Muriela has to make a split second decision about saving the dancing girl or the chest of precious gem",
        "sentence": "In \" Jewels of Gwahlur \" , he has to make a split - second decision whether to save the dancing girl Muriela or the chest of priceless gems which he spent months in search of ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Muriela",
        "question": "Who is the dancing girl in Jewels of Gwahlur?",
        "sentence": "In \" Jewels of Gwahlur \" , he has to make a split - second decision whether to save the dancing girl Muriela or the chest of priceless gems which he spent months in search of ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Muriela",
        "question": "Who does he rescue without hesitation?",
        "sentence": "So , without hesitation , he rescues Muriela and allows for the treasure to be irrevocably lost ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Black Stranger",
        "question": "In what film does Conan save Lady Belesa?",
        "sentence": "In \" The Black Stranger \" , Conan saves the exile Zingaran Lady Belesa at considerable risk to himself , giving her as a parting gift his fortune in gems big enough to have a comfortable and wealthy life in Zingara , while asking for no favors in return ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "supplant",
        "question": "What does Conan do when he is in a robber gang?",
        "sentence": "Reviewer Jennifer Bard also noted that when Conan is in a pirate crew or a robber gang led by another male , his tendency is to subvert and undermine the leader 's authority , and eventually supplant ( and often , kill ) him ( e.g."
    },
    {
        "answer": "supplant",
        "question": "What does Conan do when he is in a robber gang?",
        "sentence": "Reviewer Jennifer Bard also noted that when Conan is in a pirate crew or a robber gang led by another male , his tendency is to subvert and undermine the leader 's authority , and eventually supplant ( and often , kill ) him ( e.g."
    },
    {
        "answer": "supplant",
        "question": "What does Conan do when he is in a robber gang?",
        "sentence": "Reviewer Jennifer Bard also noted that when Conan is in a pirate crew or a robber gang led by another male , his tendency is to subvert and undermine the leader 's authority , and eventually supplant ( and often , kill ) him ( e.g."
    }
]